How did the Czech Republic's territory
change over time? The story begins in
the sixth century when Slavic tribes
migrated west into central Europe.
According to legend, their forefather
Czech climbed a mountain and founded the
nation. These tribes later formed the
empire of Great Moravia. After it
collapsed, the center of power shifted
to Prague, creating the medieval kingdom
of Bohemia. At its peak in the 13th
century, Bohemia was a major European
power, stretching from its heartland all
the way to the Adriatic Sea. But the
kingdom was eventually absorbed into the
massive Austrian Hapsburg Empire. And
for 400 years, the Czech lands had no
independence. After the Hapsburgs
collapsed in World War I, the new nation
of Czechoslovakia was born in 1918. But
in 1938, the country was betrayed and
carved up by Nazi Germany. During World
War II, it disappeared from the map
completely. After the war,
Czechoslovakia was restored, but it fell
under the control of the Soviet Union.
Finally, in 1993, in a peaceful velvet
divorce, the country split, creating the
modern Czech Republic we know